carrier.com 2012-06-23

# 

### Privacy Policy

This Privacy Statement covers how UTC Climate, Controls & Security System (“CCS”) collects and treats information received via its web site. At CCS we believe that, as our online visitor, you have a right to know our practices regarding the information we collect when you visit our websites, and what type of information is collected. The guidelines contained herein only apply to your visits to CCS websites, such as www.carrier.com, which is operated by CCS. This includes web pages on www.carrier.com that contain "carrier.com" in their URLs, but does not include any redirect URLs that link the user to another internet domain.

## Information Collection and Use

Some portions of the web site may request that a user complete a registration form. We send users who register at www.carrier.com or register their products a welcoming email to confirm their registration. Registered customers may elect to receive information on products, services, announcements and special offers. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Users who have provided personal information on www.carrier.com may occasionally be contacted with product offers if they have elected to receive this information. We will communicate with the user to provide requested services with regards to issues relating to their requests via email or phone.

A user also has the option to register their products via the web sites (product registration). During product registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name, address, and email address) and the model and serial number of the product being registered. Optional demographic information may also be collected.

A user has the option to submit a question or concern via the web sites using a customer service / contact form. The user is required to provide name and email address and contact information so that we can answer their question or request. Also, the customer service / contact form may also be routed to our third party service provider, who assists CCS in answering customer requests from our web sites.

You can send certain content to your friends. To do so, we ask you to provide your name and your friend’s email address. We use this information to send the content to your friend. A user has the option to request that CCS contact them regarding how to become a Carrier dealer on the residential.carrier.com web site. The user is required to provide name, email address and other contact information so that we can respond to their request.

Site registration, product registration, become a dealer, and customer service/contact form information is collected by CCS. An automatic email confirmation is sent to the user when they submit each of these forms.

If you email us through the “Contact Us” link on this site, we ask you for information such as your name and email address so we can respond to your questions and comments. You may choose to provide additional information as well.

## Cookies

Like many companies, we use browser cookies on this web site. Browser cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain web sites. We use browser cookies to tell us, for example, whether you’ve visited us before or if you’re a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Browser cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. The “help” portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new browser cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new browser cookie, and how to disable existing browser cookies. Remember though, without browser cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of all our web site features.

For each visitor to a CCS website, CCS’s web server automatically recognizes and stores information, such as the visitor's IP address/domain name combination and any referring websites. We use this information to understand visitor traffic patterns through our websites for purposes such as enhancing their usability. Your computer provides this information automatically each time you log on, unless you've activated blocking technology available in some browsers.

## Web Beacons

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Certain pages on our site may contain “web beacons” (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party. We use log files to store the data that is collected through web beacons. CCS also uses third party web beacons to help manage online advertising. These web beacons are provided by our ad management partners, such as Google Analytics and Omniture. These files enable Google Analytics and Omniture to recognize a unique cookie on your web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our web site. The cookie on your web browser was placed by CCS, or by another advertiser who works with Google Analytics. With both cookies and web beacon technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. For more information about Google Analytics, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to www.google-analytics.com. For more information about Omniture, including how to opt out of these technologies, go towww.omniture.com.

## Sharing

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information about our web site visitors, without your prior authorization. We may share information provided by our visitors to carrier.com with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf. These service providers are contractually restricted from using or disclosing the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided through this web site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

## Links

Our site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that CCS is not responsible for the privacy practices of third party sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy policies of any web site you visit that may collect personally identifiable information.

## Surveys

We occasionally may ask visitors to our web site to complete online surveys and opinion polls about their activities, attitudes and interests. These surveys help us serve you better and improve the usefulness of our site. In conducting these surveys we may collect personal information such as your name and email address or demographic information such as zip code or age level. We do not keep any personal information about you in connection with your participation in a carrier.com survey unless you specifically agree to provide that information.

## Supplementation of Information

We collect certain aggregate and non-personal information when you visit this web site. Aggregate and non-personal information does not relate to a single identifiable visitor. It tells us such things as how many users visited our site and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our web site to our visitors. We collect this information either through “cookie” technology or with “web beacons,” as explained above.

## Notification of Changes

This Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our online information practices. We will post a prominent notice on this web site to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Statement and indicate at the top of the statement when it was most recently updated. Changes to this Privacy Statement are effective at the time they are posted to this Site, and your continued use of this Site after posting will constitute acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those changes.

## Transfer of Info to Foreign Countries

We may transfer the personal information we collect on this site to other countries where we do business, but we will do so only for the purposes described above. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described here unless otherwise required by applicable laws.

## Consent to Processing

By providing any personal information to the CCS websites, all users, including without limitation users in the member states of the European Union, fully understand and unambiguously consent to the collection and processing of such information in the United States of America.

## Children's Privacy

This web site is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the site. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on the site, we will delete the information from our records.

## How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by, clicking on the Contact Us link located at this site, or by writing us at:

UTC Climate, Controls & Security Systems  
One Carrier Place Farmington, CT 06032

Last updated by the CCS Intellectual Property Department on December 19, 2011

Copyright © 2011 UTC Climate, Controls & Security Systems. All rights reserved.
